<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="rulesSections">
        <item>Setup</item>
        <item>Character Selection</item>
        <item>Loyalty Cards</item>
        <item>Titles</item>
        <item>Game Turn</item>
        <item>Skill Checks</item>
        <item>FTL Jumps</item>
        <item>Objectives</item>        
        <item>Revealing</item>
        <item>Revealed Cylon turn</item>
        <item>Cylon ships</item>
        <item>Vipers</item>
        <item>\"Pegasus\" Expansion: Execution</item>
        <item>\"Pegasus\" Expansion: Cylon Leader</item>        
        <item>\"Pegasus\" Expansion: New Caprica phase</item>
        <item>\"Exodus\" Expansion: Conflicted Loyalties</item>
        
        <item>The Crossroads phase</item>
        
        
        
        <item>The Cylon Fleet</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection1">
        <item>1. Set the resources dials:\nFuel: 8\nFood: 8\nMorale: 10\nPopulation: 12</item>
        <item>2. Place Vipers &amp; Raptors in Reserves space. Place the Fleet token on the start space of the Jump Preparation track.</item>
        <item>3. Starting with chosen player, proceeding clockwise, each player selects a character.</item>
        <item>4. Give President, Admiral &amp; CAG title cards to the players playing with first available character on adequate Line of Succesion.</item>
        <item>5. The Admiral is given the nuke tokens, President draws one random Quorum card.</item>
        <item>6. Create Loyalty Deck. Deal each player his Loyalty card. Add \"<i>You Are a Sympathizer</i>\" card if playing 4 or 6 player game without Cylon Leader.</item>
        <item>7. Shuffle the Quorum deck, Crisis deck, Destination deck, Skill decks &amp; Super Crisis deck.</item>
        <item>8. Each player, except the starting player, draws 3 Skill cards.</item>
        <item>9. Create Destiny Deck by drawing 2 cards of each skill.</item>
        <item>10. Place 1 Basestar &amp; 3 Raiders in front of Galactica, 2 random civilian ships behind her and 2 Vipers below her.</item>
        <item>11. First player starts his/her turn.</item>
    </string-array> 
    <string-array name="rulesSection2">
        <item>Characters are divided into 4 groups: military leaders, political leaders, pilots &amp; support.</item>
        <item>Each player chooses a character of the type that is most plentiful at his/her turn.</item>
        <item>Support characters may be chosen at any time.</item>    
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection3">
        <item>Loyalty cards are kept secret from other players.</item>
        <item>If a player has at least one \"<i>You Are a Cylon</i>\" card, he/she is a Cylon player and ignores all his/her \"<i>You Are Not a Cylon</i>\" cards.</item>
        <item>\"<i>You Are a Sympathizer</i>\" card must be revealed and resolved immediately.</item>
        <item>Cylon player may reveal his/her identity while in the Brig, but he/she won\'t be able to use special ability from \"<i>You Are a Cylon</i>\" card.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection4">
        <item>Player with President Title Card can play one of his Quorum Cards or draw additional Quorum Card as an action. The President has a maximum hand size of 10 Quorum Cards (\"Pegasus\" &amp; \"Exodus\" Expansions). When Title Card owner changes, he/she gains all Quorum Cards owned by previous President.</item>
        <item>Player with Admiral Title Card can use Nuke as an action and decides destination of the jump.</item>
        <item>Player with CAG Title Card  chooses which space area to place the civilian ship in, whenever a game effect instructs to. If able, the civilian ship should by placed in a space area that does not already have a civilian ship in it.</item>
        <item>When Admiral or CAG Player is placed in the \"Brig\" he/she is stripped of the title and the highest player in the  Line of Succession claims it.</item>
        <item>After President, Admiral or CAG Player execution or when he/she is revealed to be a Cylon, the highest player in the Line of Succession claims their title.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection5">
        <item>1. Receive Skills</item>
        <item>2. Movement</item>
        <item>3. Action</item>
        <item>4. Crisis</item>
        <item>5. Cylon Ships Activation</item>
        <item>6. Jump Preparation</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection6">
        <item>Every cards are dealt facedown and revealed at the end of the skill check.</item>
        <item>Total strength is a difference between matching cards (cards that match a skill type listed on the Skill Check) and non-matching cards.</item>
        <item>At the beginning 2 cards from the Destiny Deck are dealt.</item>
        <item>Playing cards starts with the player to the left of the current player and ends with the current player.</item>
        <item>Played cards are shuffled &amp; total strength is calculated.</item>
        <item>If total strength is equal or greater than the skill check’s difficulty, check is passed.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection7">
        <item>The fleet jumps automatically when the fleet token reaches Auto Jump area of Jump Preparation track.</item>
        <item>Players may force the fleet to jump using FTL Control location when the fleet token is on one of the blue spaces of the Jump Preparation track. The current player rolls the dice, if 6 or less is rolled, a number of population is lost equal to the number listed on the current space of the track.</item>
        <item>After the jump all ships are removed from the board.</item>
        <item>Admiral draws 2 Destination cards, chooses and resolves one.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection8">
        <item>Human Objectives\n\nKobol (Core game)\n\nHumans win after traveling 8 or more units and performing one final jump.\n\nNew Caprica(\"Pegasus\" Expansion)\n\nAfter travelling 7 or more units game enters New Caprica phase. Humans win after Galactica reappearance and one final jump (see New Caprica phase summary).\n\nThe Ionian Nebula(\"Exodus\" Expansion)\n\nHumans win after traveling 8 or more units, resolving The Crossroads phase (see summary) and performing one final jump.</item>     
        <item>Cylon Objective\nCylons win the game by preventing humans continue their journey. They can archive it when:\nAt least one resource is depleted to 0 at the end of player\'s turn.\nAt least one centurion marker reaches the end of the Boarding Party track.\n 6 or more Galactica locations have damage tokens at the same time.</item>   
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection9">
        <item>Revealing as a Cylon is an action.</item>     
        <item>Cylon Player can reveal while in \"Brig\", but he/she cannot perform special action on \"<i>You Are a Cylon</i>\" card.</item>
        <item>Revealed Cylon discards his/her Skill card deck down to 3 cards, loses his/her Title cards, receives Super Crisis card and moves to the \"Resurrection Ship\" location.</item> 
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection10">
        <item>Cylon Player draws 2 Skill Cards of any type. Skill Cards must come from a different skill type (\"Pegasus\" &amp; \"Exodus\" Expansions).</item>
        <item>Cylon Player may play only one Skill card into each Skill Check.</item>
        <item>Cylon Player may draw and play a Crisis card only by using the \"Caprica\" location.</item>
        <item>Cylon Player may move only to Cylon locations.</item>
        <item>Cylon Player may perform only actions listed on current location (Skill Card, character sheet actions are unavailable).</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection11">
        <item>Activated Raider performs first available action:\n1. Attack unmanned Viper\n2. Attack piloted Viper\n3. Attack civilian ship\n4. Move 1 space area towards the nearest civilian ship\n5. Attack Galactica</item>
        <item>If there are no Raiders on the board when raiders are activated, 2 raiders are launched from each Basestar.</item>
        <item>Activated Heavy Raider moves towards the nearest area with a viper launch icon. If it is activated with space area with the icon, Heavy Raider is removed from the board and a Centurion token is placed on the start space of the Boarding Party track. Additionally each Centurion token moves one space towards the Humans Lose space.</item>
        <item>When Basestar is activated, each Basestar attacks Galactica or Pegasus</item>
        <item>When Basestar - launch Raiders - is activated, each Basestar launches 3 raiders.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection12">
        <item>Unmanned Vipers may be activated from \"Command\" location.</item>
        <item>Player piloting a Viper can activate it as an action.</item>
        <item>Player enters a Viper by performing an action in \"Hangar Deck\" location.</item>
        <item>Player can leave his Viper and move to any location by discarding one of his/her Skill Cards.</item>
        <item>When a player activates a Viper, one of the following is chosen:\nLaunch a Viper\nMove\nAttack</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection13">
        <item>When a character is executed, the player controlling that character discards all his/her cards and shows all his/her \"<i>You Are Not a Cylon</i>\" cards or one \"<i>You Are a Cylon</i>\" card. Additional \"<i>You Are a Cylon</i>\" cards are (with \"<i>You Are Not a Cylon</i>\" cards) are passed facedown to other player.</item>
    	<item>If executed character was a human, Humans lose 1 Morale and player chooses new character.</item>
    	<item>If executed character was a Cylon, normal procedure for a revealed Cylon is followed, but player do not draw a Super Crisis card.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection14">
        <item>There may be only one Cylon Leader in game.</item>
        <item>Cylon Leader Player follows normal rules for revealed Cylon Player.</item>
        <item>Cylon Leader can Infiltrate the fleet. During Infiltration Cylon Leader Player is treated like Human Player.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="rulesSection15">
        <item>During this phase, Crisis cards are drawn from the New Caprica Crisis deck and players move only on New Caprica board. Cylon ship activation icons on Crisis cards are ignored.</item>
        <item>Cylon Players start this phase on \"Occupation Authority\" location, Human Players on \"Resistance HQ\" location.</item>
        <item>\"Detention\" location is treated as a \"Brig\" location. Player sent to \"Detention\" does not lose his/her Title Card.</item>
        <item>Human Player can attack occupation forces in his/her location as an action. If roll result is 5 or higher 1 occupation forces token in player\'s location is removed from the board.</item>
        <item>Cylon Player can detain Human Player in his/her location as an action if there is an occupation forces token in this location. If roll result is 1&#8211;3, the human is moved to \"Detention\", if result is 4&#8211;7 the human is moved to \"Medical Center\".</item>
        <item>Each time occupation forces are activated, tokens are moved one space on the track along the bottom of the board. If an occupation forces token on the \"Shipyard\" location is activated, remove it from the game board and destroy 1 civilian ship.</item>
        <item>When the fleet marker reaches the Auto Jump space of the Jump Preparation track, Galactica returns to orbit and evacuation phase begins. Place a Basestar and 4 Raiders in each of the 2 space areas above Galactica and launch 2 Vipers. Cylon ship activation icons are no longer ignored. Players may move between New Caprica and other locations.</item>
        <item>When an evacuation icon is revealed on a New Caprica Crisis card, 1 civilian ship is moved from the top of the Prepared Civilian Ships stack to any space area with a Viper launch icon.</item>
        <item>After Galactica\'s return, the Admiral may, as an action, order Galactica to leave. After this jump all civilian ships left on New Caprica are destroyed. If subsequently no resource has been reduced to 0 or lower, the humans win.</item>
   </string-array>
   <string-array name="rulesSection16">
       <item>Personal Goal Loyalty cards, the Final Five Loyalty cards, or both may be used. These cards are treated like \"<i>You Are Not a Cylon</i>\" cards.</item>
       <item>Personal Goal Loyalty card contains an action that allows the player who received it to reveal the card, only if the conditions described on the card are all currently true.</item>
       <item>If player revealed his/her Personal Goal Loyalty card before fleet has traveled at least 7 units, he/she shuffles the top card from the \"<i>You Are Not a Cylon</i>\" deck into the Loyalty Deck and draws new Loyalty card.</item>
       <item>Unrevealed Personal Goal Loyalty cards that belong to Human Players, at the end of the game reduces some resources.</item>
       <item></item>
   </string-array>
</resources>